Ciaran Carson papers, circa 1970-2010
Emory University
- Printed material, 1975-2008, Series 4; Boxes 32 - 40, 61-62; OP 6 - 26
  - Printed material by Carson, 1975-2007, Subseries 4.1; Box 32 - Box 34, 61; OP6 - 12
    - "Aranmore Ireland 2. "The Fault" in The Irish Press, undated (Box OP6, Folder -)
    - "Aranmore Ireland 3. "American Wake" in The Irish Press, undated (Box OP6, Folder -)
    - "Artwork Old as the Hills," [essay] in Belfast Review, March-May 1985 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "Athlone through Hilversum," fragment of poem used as promotional material (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "Az Elfeledett Város," [poem] in Magyar Napló, January 2005 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - "Basin and Range," [review of Peter Redgrove and Penelope Shuttle] in Poetry London, summer 2000 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - "Bats, Balls, and Boozers," [review of Tony Collins and Wray Vamplew] in The Guardian, 20 July 2002 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - "Bedtime Story," corrected proof with TLS from Alice; Quinn and copy of The New Yorker, 6 November 1989 [See also Subseries 4.1: "Ambition"] (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "Belfast Notes," in TLS, 18-24 March 1988 [see also Subseries 2.4: "Belfast Notes," TS for TLS, 18-24 March 1988] (Box OP7, Folder -)
    - "Belfast Notes," in TLS, 24-30 June 1988 [See also Subseries 2.4: "Belfast Notes," TS and proof, for TLS, 24-30 June 1988] (Box OP8, Folder -)
    - "Bloody Hand," [poem] in The New Yorker, 25 April 1994 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Call of the Ould Orange Flutes," [essay] in Belfast Review, summer 1984 [See also Subseries 2.4: Last Night's Fun typescripts] (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "A Captious and Irritable Race," [essay] in Belfast Review, autumn 1986 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "Ciaran Carson Interviewed," [interview by Frank Ormsby] Linen Hall Review, spring 1991 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - "Clocks Ticking, Tractors Passing" [essay] in Belfast Review, winter 1986 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - "Colmcille's Return," [poem] The Irish Press, undated [Dublin] (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - "Come Dance with Me in Irlaunde," [essay] in Belfast Review, autumn 1983 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "Dante Among the Giants: A Translation of the Inferno, Canto XXXI," proof and published poem from TLS 29 September 2000 (Box OP9, Folder -)
    - "Dante: Inferno Canto V," [translation] in Poetry Review, summer 2001 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "A Dash of Color," [essay] in The Dublin Review, spring 2002 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - "Dead Happy," [poem] in Poetry Review, winter 1997/1998 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - "The Dead Man's Breeches" [essay] in Belfast Review, autumn 1982 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - "The Dialects of Silence," [review of Ted Mcarthy, Bernard O'Donoghue, Carol Rumens, Aiden Matthews] in Poetry London, summer 1999 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Dziennik Portowy [Legnica Poetry Festival journal], includes interview and translations of Carson, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - "Escape" [essay] in the Scottish Sunday Times, 12 December 1999 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - "Escaped from the Massacre? North by Seamus Heaney," [review] in The Honest Ulsterman, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - "Gaeltacht," [poem] The Irish Press, undated [Dublin] (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - "Gate," in "Four Poems," [poem] TLS, 17-23 March 1989 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - "Hamlet" [poem] galley proof for London Review of Books, 2 October 1989 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - "Hamlet," in London Review of Books, 2 March 1989 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - "The Horse's Mouth: Some Thoughts on Translation" [essay] in Tank, 2003 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - "House Rules O.K.," [essay] in Belfast Review, summer 1986 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - "Inkerman Street," [poem] in The Living Stream: A Festschrift for Theo Dorgan (2000) (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Introduction," [essay introducing unknown book] [variant title: "Country Roads" when used as chapter in Last Night's Fun], circa 1995 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "Is There Somebody Up There Listening?" [essay] in Belfast Review, spring 1983 [See also Subseries 2.2: "Is There Somebody Up There Listening?"] (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - It Is Probably the Irish, [translations] Carson translated by Piotr Sommer, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - "Jacta Est Alea," [poem] in irland almanach, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - "Jump Leads," in "Four Poems," [poem] TLS March 17-23, 1989 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - "Laces and Eyelets," [essay] in Source: Ireland's Photography Review, autumn/winter 1997 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - "The Language Instinct," [essay] in The Guardian, 1 May 2004 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - "Last Orders," in "Four Poems," [poem] TLS 17-23 March 1989 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - "Learning to Read Between the Notes," [essay] in Belfast Review, December 1985-February 1986 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - "Lost and Found," [essay] in Source, winter 2000 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - "A Lot of Buzzing Around the Bush; and also a Poet to Enjoy," [review of Jorie Graham and Kit Wright] in Poetry London, spring 2001 [See also Subseries 2.4: "Many Mansions" for TS and proofs of review] (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - "Many Riches in a Small," [essay] in Belfast Review, winter 1983 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - "Me Gusta la Libertad Que Ofrece la Prosa," [interview] in Lateral: Revista de Cultura, June 2005 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - "Mick Hoy, Derrygonnelly: An Appreciation," [obituary] in The Fermanagh Herald, 21 June 2000 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - "Modus operandi," [essay] in PBS Bulletin, August 1996 with TLS from Clare Brown (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - "The Night Before, the Morning After," introduction to Tom Mac Intyre's play, Sheep's Milk on the Boil, 17 February 1994 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - "O," in The Independent on Sunday, 23 May 1999 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - "O'Carolan's Complaint," [poem] The Irish Press, undated [Dublin] (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - "Opus Operandi," in London Review of Books, 27 May 1993 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - "Our Master's Voices" [essay] in Belfast Review, summer 1983 [See also Subseries 2.2: "Our Master's Voices"] (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - "Playing It by the Good Book" [essay] in Belfast Review, autumn 1984 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - "Rainy Liasons," [poem] [See Subseries 4.1: "Dead Happy"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Redoubt" and "Treaty" [poems] in Poetry London, summer 2007 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - "The Riddle of the Sands," [poem] in The Southern Review, summer 1995 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - "The Room," [poem] from "Versions After Mallarme" in unknown source. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Russia," [poem] in The New Yorker, 2 December 2002 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - "The Swan," [poem] [See Subseries 4.1: "The Room"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Tales within Tales," [Interview with Ian Kilroy] in The Irish Times, 6 November 1999 (Box OP11, Folder -)
    - "This is what libraries are for," [essay] in The Dublin Review, autumn 2001 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "A Time of Reds and Blues" [essay] in Belfast Review, spring 1984 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - "The Tomb," [poem] [See Subseries 4.1: "The Room"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Turn Again," [poem] [See Subseries 4.1: "Bloody Hand"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Way to Say a Thing,"[essay] in Poetry Book Society Bulletin, autumn 1999, with TLS from Clare Brown (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - "The Well of Saints," The Irish Press, undated [Dublin] (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "Translating Dante" [speech given at the University of Notre Dame International Dante Seminar] 26 September 2003 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - "What I Did on Mes Vacances," [essay] in Belfast Review, September-November 1985 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "Wheel" [poem] in The Irish Press, undated (Box OP6, Folder -)
    - "When Memory Goes Blank," [essay] in Newsday, 7 October 2001 [variant title: "Living in Troubled Times;" See also Subseries 2.4: "Living in Troubled Times"] (Box OP12, Folder -)
    - "Whiskey," [poem translated into German] in Warenmuster, blühend (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "Yes," in "Four Poems," [poem] TLS 17-23 March 1989 (Box OP10, Folder -)
    - Miscellaneous printed material by Carson (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Printed material about Carson, 1976-2008, Subseries 4.2; Box 34-38, 61-62; OP 13 - 21
    Arranged by record type.
    - Articles and Essays
    - "Belfast Confetti - der metallische Regen," in LVZ (Berlin), 29 June 1993 [See also Series 1: Correspondence from British Council, 2 July 1993] (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - "Carson's Sense of Place: His Way of Describing Belfast," by Ryoji Okuda in The Harp (IASIL-Japan Bulletin Vol. XIII), 1998 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - "Ciaran Carson: La Poesia Risonante,"and translations of "Letters from the Alphabet: H, O," "Auditque Vocatus Apollo," "Cave Quid Dicis, Cuando et Cui," "Omne Vivum ex Ovo," "X-Ray," "Zulu," by Roberto Bertoni in Linea d'ombra, September - October 1997; with TLS from Bertoni, 3 November 1997 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - "Ciaran Carson's Parturient Partition: The 'Crack' in MacNeice's 'More than Glass," by Guinn Batten in The Southern Review, summer 1995 [See Subseries 4.1: "The Riddle of the Sands"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - A City of the Mind: Belfast in the Writings of Ciaran Carson, University of Trieste thesis by Giulio Bonacci, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - "Coriandoli di Guerra, La Belfast Polifonica de Ciaran Carson," by Giovanni Pillonca in Il Manifesto, August 1998 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Edinburgh International Book Festival, 20 August 2006 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - "The Evolving Art of Ciaran Carson," by Ben Howard in Shenandoah, Spring 1998 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - "Exploded Diagrams," by Caitríona O'Reilly in Dublin Review, autumn 2001 [See Subseries 4.1: "This is what libraries are for," by Carson] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "First Impressions, Second Thoughts," by David Burleigh in Haiku: Haiku Magazine in English (spring-summer 1991), with TLS from Burleigh, 28 May 1991 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Gendaishi Techo, (October 2001) Japanese literary journal with article on Carson's Fishing for Amber; includes TLS from Nobuaki Tochigi, 27 October 2001 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - "Hummable Sonnets, Brechtian Monologues," [review of The Twelfth of Never] by John Harley Williams in Poetry London, summer 2001 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - "Introduction to the Poetry of Ciaran Carson," by Nobuaki Tochigi in Eureka 2 (2000) [with translation into Japanese of "Antipodes" from Fishing for Amber] (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "The Irish Times - Aer Lingus 1990 Literature Prizes," The Irish Times, 8 September 1990 [folder also includes Carson's "Barfly" and "The Knee"] (Box OP13, Folder -)
    - "The Irony of Northern Ireland and the War With Words: A Conversation with Ciaran Carson," by Thomas Rain Crowe in The Blooomsbury Review, November/December 2000 [See also Subseries 2.6: interview of Ciaran Carson by Thomas Rain Crowe] (Box OP14, Folder -)
    - "It's not so much about Belfast as of Belfast," The Irish Times, 13 October 1990 (Box OP13, Folder -)
    - "Letters from the Alphabet: Carson's and Muldoon's Contingent Poetics," in Irish Poetry: Politics, History, Negotiation (1997) by Steven Matthews (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "Mapping the Trenches: Gyres, Switchbacks and Zig-Zag Circles in W. B. Yeats and Ciaron Carson," by Frank Brearton in Irish Studies Review, 2001 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - "Narrative Metamorphoses in Ciaron Caron's Fishing for Amber: A Long Story" by Nobuaki Tochigi in the Journal of Irish Studies, September 2001 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - "Poesia Inglese: La Generazione Degli Anni Settanta," by Edoardo Zuccato in Poesia, September 1997 [includes translations of "Collecting Stamps," "Belfast Confetti," and "The Irish for No"] (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "Quella pace critta sui muri," [interview of Carson] in l'Unita (Italian newspaper), 22 October 1996 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - "A Republic of Poets," by Michael Hartnett in The Irish Press (?), 1972 [review of Soundings 72, edited by Seamus Heaney and including selected Carson poems] (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - "Reeling with Words: Music and Intoxication in Ciaran Carson's Alphabetical Sequences," by Nobuaki Tochigi in The Harp (IASIL-Japan Bulletin Vol. XIII), 1998 [See Subseries 4.2: "Carson's Sense of Place," by Ryoji Okuda] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "'That Blank Month': Secrecy, Shibboleths, and Silence in Northern Irish Poetry,'" by David Wheatley in Journal of Modern Literature, 2002 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - "This is Radio Carson," by Michael Hinds in The Harp (IASIL-Japan Bulletin Vol. XIII), 1998 [See Subseries 4.2: "Carson's Sense of Place," by Ryoji Okuda] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Tussen Aanhalingstekens: Over de Poëzie van Ciaran Carson," by Peter Nijmeijer in De Gids, October 1997 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "War and Verse," by Thomas O'Dwyer in The Jerusalem Post, 11 June 1999 [See Subseries 4.2: OP15] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Assorted articles relating to Ciaran Carson [1976-2003] (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Assorted articles about Carson (Box OP15, Folder -)
    - Reviews and Clippings
    - Reviews and clippings of The New Estate (1976) (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Reviews and clippings of Pocket Guide to Irish Traditional Music (1986) (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Irish for No (1987) (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Irish for No (1987) (Box OP16, Folder -)
    - Reviews and clippings of Belfast Confetti (1989) (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Reviews and clippings of First Language (1994) (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Reviews and clippings of First Language (1994) (Box OP17, Folder -)
    - Reviews and clippings of Opera Et Cetera (1996) (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Reviews and clippings of Last Night's Fun (1996) (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Star Factory (1997) (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Star Factory (1997) (Box OP18, Folder -)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Alexandrine Plan (1998) (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Twelfth of Never (1998-2001) (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Ballad of HMS Belfast (1999) (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Best Poetry CD in the WorldEver! (1999) (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Reviews and clippings of Fishing for Amber (2000) (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Reviews and clippings of Fishing for Amber (2000) (Box OP19, Folder -)
    - Reviews and clippings of Shamrock Tea (2001) (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Reviews and clippings of Shamrock Tea (2001) (Box OP20, Folder -)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Inferno (2002-2007) (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Reviews and clippings of Breaking News (2003) (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Midnight Court (2005) (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Reviews and clippings of The Táin (2007) (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Reviews and clippings of Bear in Mind These Dead (2008) (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Reviews and clippings of For All We Know (2008) (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Promotional Material
    - Bloodaxe Books (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Farrar Straus Giroux (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Gallery Press (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Granta Books (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Jonathan Cape (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Poetry Book Society (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Wake Forest University Press (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous promotional materials (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Readings and Appearances
    - Kirkland College (Clinton, NY) and Wake Forest University (Winston Salem, NC), from 4 March 1977 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Newcastle University Literary Society, 16 February 1978 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Grassroots Program of the North Carolina Arts Council, Irish Writers and Musicians, 19 March 1981 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - 5th Orkney Traditional Folk Festival, Scotland, 21-24 May 1987 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Oxford-Ireland Cultural Festival, 10-18 June 1988 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - The Irish for No--U.S. promotional tour, October 1988 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - The Smithsonian Institution, 25 October 1988 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - National Poetry Centre, London, 21 September 1989 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - St. Andrews Poetry Festival, Scotland, 20 April 1990 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - W. B. Yeats International Theatre Festival, 19 August 1990 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - "Stories, Songs & Poems from Northern Ireland," Brussels, 12 December 1990 (Box OP21, Folder -)
    - Irish Arts Festival in London, 14 February 1991 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - IASAIL, Netherlands, 9-13 July 1991 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Scoil Shliabh gCuillinn, 13-15 November 1992 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Festival of Irish Literature, Warsaw, 24-30 April 1993 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - The Honest Ulsterman, 25th Birthday Party, 20 May 1993 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Festival de Musica Celta, Barcolona, 7-23 July 1993 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Symposium on Contemporary Poetry, Ballyearl, Mossley, 19-21 November 1993 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - The Academy of American Poets Reading, 3 May 1994 (Box OP21, Folder -)
    - Canadian Association for Irish Studies Conference, 11-14 May 1994 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - The Hay Festival, Wales, 20-30 May 1994 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Yeats International Summer School, Sligo, Ireland, 6-20 August 1994 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - British Studies Conference, Tallinn, Estonia, 27-28 August 1994 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Aspects: A Celebration of Irish Writing, Bangor, 30 September 1994 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Poetry International at South Bank Centre, London, 30 October 1994 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - An Evening of Irish Poetry, Emory University, 23 February 1995 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Waterstone's Booksellers, 23 May 1995 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Le voci della poesia, University of Bologna, 29 May 1995 [See also OP21 for publicity poster] (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Milwaukee Irish Fest, 18-20 August 1995 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - World Poetry Festival, Huddersfield, England, 7 October 1995 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Here's Us: Belfast First Festival of Writers and Writing, 12-15 October 1995 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Blackstaff Press and the English Society, Queen's College, 2 November 1995 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - New Zealand International Festival of the Arts, 16 March 1996 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - L'imaginaire Irlandis, France, 22-27 March 1996 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Glucksman Ireland House, NYU, May 1996 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Birmingham Readers and Writers Festival, 10-18 May 1996 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Waterstone's Booksellers, 23 May 1996 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Spoleto Festival USA, 3 June 1996 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - T. S. Eliot Prize 1996 Shortlist Readings, 12 January 1997 (Box OP21, Folder -)
    - Stray Dog Café, Dublin, 27 April 1997 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Poetry International Rotterdam, 20 June 1997 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Sixth William Carleton Summer School, Clogher, Ireland, 4-7 August 1997 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - T. S. Eliot Prize award ceremony 1997, 19 January 1998 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - The Belfast Arts Awards, 20 March 1998 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - "Irlande/Irlandes,"University of Paris, 25, 26 March 1998 (Box OP21, Folder -)
    - Literairtheater Branoul, Denmark, 8 April 1998 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - The Yorkshire Post Literary Luncheon honoring The Star Factory as Book of the Year, Harrogate, 21 May 1998 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Legnica Poetry Festival, Poland, 26 September 1998 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Appalachian State University, 12 November 1998 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - University of Missouri-St. Louis, 17-18, November 1998 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Southern Illinois University at Carbondale, 18 November 1998 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "Nights to Remember" at The Duke of York, Belfast 26 November 1998 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Jerusalem International Poetry Festival, 5-7 June 1999 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Aran Islands International Poetry and Prose Festival, 15-21 August 1999 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Bucknell University, 18 October 1999 [See also OP21 for publicity poster] (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Belfast Festival at Queens, 1 November 1999' (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Celtic Connections, Glasgow, 11-28 January 2000 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - St. Donats Arts Center, Wales, 4 February 2000 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - The British Council in Poland, 9 March 2000 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Finnegans Awake, San Francisco, 5-7 May 2000 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - ACIS, Limerick, 29 June 2000 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Legnica Poetry Festival, Poland, 22-25 September 2000 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Poetry International: "Versions of Dante," 6 October 2000 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Benefit Night for James Simmons, 26 October 2000 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Chicago Humanities Festival, NOW!, 2-12 November 2000 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Stories, Poems and Songs from Northern Ireland, University of Augsburg, Berlin, 29-30 January 2001 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - University of Utrecht's New Irish Writing Symposium, the Netherlands, 6 February 2001 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Creative Writers' Network Poetry Reading at Down Civic Arts Centre, 9 February 2001 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - American Conference for Irish Studies, the Southern Regional Meeting, 21 February 2001 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Wake Forest University Irish Festival, 21 March 2001 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Word 2001, University of Aberdeen Scottish Writers Festival, 18-20 May 2001 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Mind's Eye Durham Literature Festival, 15 June 2001 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Edinburgh International Book Festival, 14 August 2001 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - The T S Eliot Prize 2001, 14 January 2002 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Poetry London Competition, 14 February 2002 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Between the Lines: Belfast's Literary Festival, 20 March 2002 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Bangor Arts Festival, 23 May 2002 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Eighteenth International James Joyce Symposium, Trieste, 18 June 2002 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - University of Ulster, School of Languages and Literature, Symposium on Ciaron Carson, 12 September 2002 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - John Coffin Memorial Literary Readings at the University of London, 11 March 2003 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - The Society of Authors, the Cholmondeley Awards, 10 June 2003 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Crossing Border Festival at the Royal Theatre in the Hague, The Netherlands, 14 November 2003 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - The Irish Writers Centre, 26 February 2004 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - The Institute of Irish Studies at the University of Liverpool, 16 July 2004 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Symposium of the AHRC Irish-Scottish Poetry Project, 24 November 2006 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Lannan Symposium at Georgetown University, 18 April 2007 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Inglese D'Irlanda, reading of Inferno, 28 September 2007 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Queen's University's The Seamus Heaney Centre, 11 March 2008 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Seamus Heaney Centre for Poetry, book launch of Collected Poems, 16 October 2008 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Assorted undated readings (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Other printed material, 1976-2006, Subseries 4.3; Boxes 39-40, 62; OP 21 - 26
    - Printed Material with Literary Subjects
    - "Again," essay by Tess Gallagher [document included in packet with Gallagher's "The Leper;" See also Subseries 3.2: "Again"] (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Aversion, chaplet by Devin Johnston, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - The Brendan Kennelly Summer Festival, Stories & Silence, 7-10 August 2003 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - The British and Irish Contemporary Poetry Conference, The Line of Contemporary Poetry, 22-24 September 2006 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - "Caretaker of the Poets," article on Dillon Johnston by Sharon Parrish Bowers, in Irish America, September-October 1994 [with ALS from Candide Jones at Wake Forest University Press] (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Columbia: A Magazine of Poetry and Prose (1995) with TLS solicitation for poetry, 28 October 1995 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Curfew and Other Stories (2000) by Sean O'Reilly (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Deux Audacieux (2002) by Tess Gallagher (Box 39, Folder 6)